残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 群れのドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっとくれるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使のテーゼ 窓辺からやがて取り立つ
もっと走る熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
ご視聴ありがとうございました
シンジー wake up how long are you going to avoid school
it's been five days now unit one's already completely repaired
you're the pilot are you going to leave it sitting there
シンジー
okay well Shinji's he's at the nerve training facility right now oh I see
these are the printouts that were building up on Shinji's desk oh sorry
for your trouble thank you well we'll just be leaving now please say hi to
Shinji for us uh yeah I will bye
this is an unexpected development she was a real babe wasn't she
hmm
Shinji you idiot
jerk
the next station is Nagao toge Nagao toge
the exit will switch to the right side
toge
hmm
Thank you for using the Tokyo-3 loop line.
This train will be going out of service at this station.
Please, make sure you take all of your belongings with you as you exit the train.
Thank you for using Tokyo-3 loop line.
Huh. I ought to go back.
The tactic, Doctor!
Yeah! The object, several dozen millimeters across, crashed into a dark to get close to the speed of light!
We're going to predict such an occurrence!
It's a civic hell outside!
I just want it's the purpose of science!
The atmospheric flux caused by the change in the Earth's axis has decreased by 3%.
No! Things are...
No! There's still a tidal wave approaching at 230 meters a second!
Doctor, we must evacuate!
Nein! It's my duty to remain here!
Doctor, choosing death is easy, but you have an obligation to watch this living hell!
No!
No.
What?
Wow.
Idiot.
Nothing?
Nothing.
I don't think he's going to come back this time.
What will you do?
Nothing. It's better for him if he doesn't come back.
But why?
Because of what happened after the last battle.
Why did you ignore my orders?
I apologize.
I'm the one who's in charge of your operations, aren't I?
Yes.
You do know you're supposed to obey my orders, understand?
I'm warning you not to do it again.
Yes.
Hey, are you even listening to anything I'm saying?
Oh, no, you don't.
You're not going to get out of this by just saying yes to everything I say.
I know, Miss Misato.
We won, didn't we? Isn't that enough?
You know, it may seem easy going along with whatever anyone else wants,
but if you get into an Eva with that attitude, it'll kill you.
You know, I just don't care anymore.
It'd be nice if I could say you've got the right attitude,
but if you think you're going to get any praise out of me, you're wrong, Shinji.
That's not the point.
Anyway, I'm the only one who can pilot it.
I'll just have to do.
I see.
If getting into the Eva means nothing but pain to him, I don't think he should pilot again.
Otherwise, he'll be killed.
But we need pilots.
Captain!
Ida, go on ahead.
But I can't go on and leave you behind like this.
What will I do?
You fool!
There.
The new kid!
Ikari!
Told you was real sorry about everything.
His kid's sister really tore him a new one.
She said that it was the robot who saved her lives.
That must be pretty embarrassing,
getting herself chewed out by a second grader.
Right?
Hmm.
I like it out here at night
because those noisy cicadas don't chirp.
It was pretty quiet when I was a kid,
but there are tons of them now.
Misato said...
Huh?
That the ego system is returning to its former state.
Misato said so, hmm?
I really envy you.
I mean, you live with such a beautiful woman
and you get the power of the Evangelion.
Oh, man.
I wish I could get inside that lovely cockpit just once.
You really shouldn't, you know.
Your mother would probably be worried.
Huh?
Oh, don't worry about my mother.
I don't have one of those.
Oh.
I'm no different from you.
You'll take something to eat, won't you?
Yeah.
Do you usually do things like this?
Well, sure.
Is it some kind of training for guerrilla warfare or something?
How could I fight with toys like these?
It's just for fun.
You're Shinji Akari, aren't you?
Huh?
Hmm?
Hey!
Ah!
You're Shinji Akari, aren't you?
Yes.
We're from the Nerve Security Intelligence.
Under Security Clause Article 8,
we're taking you to Nerve Headquarters.
All right?
Yes.
And all you did was stand there?
That's easy for you to say,
but they were nerve intelligence professionals.
So what about it?
Jeez, don't you have any balls at all?
Girl, pervert, ape.
Only an idiot fights when he knows you can't win.
Balls have nothing to do with it.
Long time no see.
Yeah.
Do you feel any better after wandering around for two days?
I don't know.
The Ava is on standby.
Will you pilot it?
Or won't you?
You're not going to scold me for running away?
Of course you're not.
I'm no relation to you, am I?
If I say that I won't pilot Unit 1,
what are you going to do with it?
I suppose that Rey will do it.
You won't pilot it?
It seems a little bit unrealistic
for you to force everything on her.
Don't worry.
I'll pilot it.
But you don't want to do it.
Of course not.
It's not something that comes to me naturally.
But Ayanami and you and Miss Ritsuko...
Stop that line of crap!
This has nothing to do with any of us.
If you don't like it, get out of here.
Just forget all about Ava and us
and go back where you came from.
We don't need someone with that attitude, piloting.
You do know that the third child is leaving Tokyo 3 tomorrow, don't you?
We'll reconfigure Unit 1's system for Rey.
Regardless of the results of the Unit 0 reactivation experiments,
we'll move on to experimenting on Unit 1.
According to the Marduk organization's report,
the fourth child hasn't been found yet.
Does that mean we can't get any more pilot recruits?
Uh, excuse me.
Where is Miss Misato?
I'd like to say goodbye.
You are no longer NERV personnel.
Therefore, we can't give you that information.
Hey, Kari!
Huh?
Hey, you left this stuff behind!
Oh!
Uh, excuse me.
Could I...
Um...
Well...
Thank you.
Hey, Tauji!
Come on, say something!
Kari, look.
I'm sorry about hitting you twice.
Please, you gotta hit me back.
I can't do that!
You gotta.
Otherwise, I won't be satisfied.
He's a pretty embarrassing guy, isn't he?
But if it'll put an end to this dispute,
why don't you go ahead and hit him?
But I...
Hurry up!
You don't have much time, do you?
Okay.
But only once.
Right!
Come on!
Hey, wait!
Don't hold back.
Oh, that hurt.
How do you know I'd be here?
Uh, it was just a hunch.
We've seen lots of other classmates off before.
It's getting to be a regular thing.
Of course, if you're leaving, you know,
we'll have to leave this city sometime soon.
But we can't really blame you for that.
I mean, we saw how you suffered in the Eva.
Uh, and anyway, if anyone does try to blame you,
I'm gonna give him a whop on the head!
Come on!
Try not to look so gloomy.
Take care, Ikari.
Yeah, take care.
Well, uh...
Your time is up.
Huh?
Uh...
I'm the one who deserved to be hit, not you!
I'm a coward!
I'm dishonest!
I'm sneaky!
And a wimp!
Don't give us any more trouble.
Jeez!
Well, he's gone.
Do you really think this is for the best?
The hedgehog's dilemma.
The closer we become, the more deeply we hurt.
Now I understand.
I finally understand.
He can't let others know how he feels in any other way.
Express linear train bound for Atsuki is arriving on track two.
For your safety, please step back to the area inside the yellow lines.
The train arriving on track two is for special government use only.
It departs at 420 for Atsuki.
No civilians are allowed inside the fence.
Please be aware that the boarding of this train by unauthorized persons is strictly prohibited.
Hang in there.
Huh?
.
Hey, look!
That's the babe!
Ah...
Huh?
Hmm...
The local train bound for Gora is now arriving on Track 4.
For your own safety, please stay inside the yellow lines.
If you are accompanying small children, please ensure that they are properly supervised.
The train arriving on Track 4 is the local shuttle to Gora, departing at 432.
If this is your train, please step inside and wait until departure.
The train is approaching. Please stay behind the yellow line.
I... I'm home!
Welcome home.
Okay.
won't belong and support all of your answers.
I'll see you in third and repeat.
Yeah, yes, I won't.
Over other years, I'm here.
Hello, thanks.
The 잡아...
Little, too.
Tommy, baby!
Do you wanna tour the healing process that you can navigate?
Alright.
So we should be coming next.
In other words, darling, kiss me
Fill my heart with song, girl, let me sing forevermore
You are all I long for, all I worship and adore
In other words, please be true
In other words, I love you
Rei Ayanami seems cold and distant, yet she seems to have a relationship with Commander Ikari
Shenji doesn't understand how this can be, but before he can find out more
A beam shot by the fifth angel strikes Ava Unit 1 in the chest
Will this episode be Shenji's last?